Guide to the Roland Park Company Records, ca. 1891-1962
Roland Park Company Records, ca. 1891-1962
- Series III. Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s 1917 correspondence
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to James Posey re Gould job, Jan. 2, 1917 (Box 111)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Henry P. Westheimer, Jan. 25,1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Henry P. Westheimer, Feb. 7,1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Henry P. Westheimer, Feb. 9, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Henry P. Westheimer, Feb. 15, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Henry P. Westheimer, Feb. 19, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer Jr.'s cc. to Henry P. Westheimer, Feb. 27, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Mar. 19, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Apr. 11,1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Apr. 16, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Apr. 18-20, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Apr. 26, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, May 4, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, May 10, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, May 15, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, May 21, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, May 26, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, June 2, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, June 22, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, June 25 and 27, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Aug. 13, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Aug. 15, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to Francis A. White, Aug. 18, 1917 (Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous 1918 Files (I-P) (Box 117)
  - Edward L. Palmer, Jr.'s cc. to George W. Knapp, Mar. 7, 1918 (Box 117)
- Series IV. Bound Volumes
  Some of these are standing on the shelf rather than in boxes
  - "Current General" Ledgers (7 volumes), 1919-1957
  - "Baltimore County" Leger (1 volume), 1930-1939
  - "General Ledger, Transfer" (5 volumes), 1910-1955
  - Ledger (1 volume), 1906-1907
  - Ledger, "Guilford Park Co." (1 volume), 1907-1908
  - "Expense" Ledger (1 volume), 1940-1959
  - "General Ledger Subsidiary" (1 volume), 1934-1946
  - Roland Park Montebello Co. Sales Journal (1 volume), 1930-1935
  - Scrap Book, newspaper clippings (1 volume), n.d.
  - Roland Park Co. Transfer Book (1 volume), 1892-1920
  - R.P. Homeland Co., Notes Receivable, Transfer (1 volume), 1929-1940
  - One photograph book (printed)-"Homeland," "Northwood," and "Dundalk" (Box 341)
  - Two Legers (2 volumes), 1912-1914
- Series V. Ledgers and Portfolios
  - Ledger B (volume 1), 1895-1897 (Box 344)
  - Ledger C (volume 2), 1897-1900
  - Ledger D (volume 3), 1901-1902
  - Ledger E (volume 4), 1903-1906
  - Ledger F (volume 5), 1907-1909
  - General Ledger (volume 6), 1910-1911 (Box 344)
  - General Ledger (volume 7), 1911-1912 (Box 344)
  - General Ledger (volume 8), 1912-1913 (Box 345)
  - General Ledger (volume 9), 1912-1913 (Box 345)
  - General Ledger #1 (volume 10), 1914 (Box 345)
  - General Ledger #2 (volume 11), 1914 (Box 346)
  - General Ledger (volume 12), 1919-1925 (Box 346)
  - General Ledger( volume 13), 1921-1925 (Box 347)
  - General Ledger (volume 14), 1925-1933 (Box 347)
  - Notes Receivable (volume 15), 1926-1935 (Box 347)
  - General Ledger (volume 16), 1926-1933 (Box 348)
  - General Ledger (volume 17), 1928-1940 (Box 348)
  - General Ledger (volume 18), 1930-1933 (Box 349)
  - Ledger B (volume 19), 1934-1948 (Box 349)
  - General Ledger(volume 20), 1934-1939 (Box 350)
  - Sales Journal (volume 21), 1930-1935 (Box 351)
  - General Ledger (volume 22), 1940-1959 (Box 351)
  - General Ledger (volume 23), 1940-1957 (Box 351)
  - Expense Ledger (volume 24), 1940-1959 (Box 351)
  - Portfolio (volume 25)
  - Portfolio (volume 26)
  - Portfolio (volume 27)
  - Portfolio (volume 28)
  - Portfolio (volume 29)
  - Portfolio (volume 30)
  - Portfolio (volume 31)
  - Northwood photos-land and street construction (volume 32)
- Series VI. Record plats for Guilford
  - Original Plat-Sheet #1, May 1913 (Map-case O10)
  - Blocks 29A and 30. Subdivision of Block 29, March 15, 1915 (Map-case O10)
  - Plat map, May 1921 (Map-case O10)
  - Plat map, July 1, 1927 (Map-case O10)
  - Plat map, rev., Jamuary 2, 1942 (Map-case O10)
- Series VII. Record plats not held by Cornell
  - Guilford
    - Original Plat-Sheet #2, May 1913
    - Original Plat-Sheet #3, May 1913
    - Lots South of University Parkway (#4), May 12,1913
    - Portions of Blocks 44, 46 and 48 (#4), June 5, 1914
    - Resubdivision-Lots 8, 9, 10, 11, 17, 18, 19 and 20-Block 28 (#5), June 26, 1914
    - Resubdivision-Lots 2, 15 and 16-Block 2 (#5), June 26, 1914
    - Resubdivision-Blocks 31 to 35 and 39 (#6), Oct. 19, 1914
    - Resubdivision-Lots 1, 2, 17, 18 and 19-Block 45 (#6), Nov. 4, 1914
    - Block 29-A and 20-A Resubdivision of Block 29 (#7), May 15, 1915
    - Subdivision of Block 10 (#7), Oct. 12, 1915
    - Land on S.W. side of Charles Street (#8), Dec. 17, 1915
    - Southway Subdivision (#8), Dec. 23, 1915
    - Resubdivision of Blocks 9, 10, 23 and 39 and parts of Blocks 3, 8 and 38 (#9), July 5, 1921
    - Resubdivision of parts of Blocks 53 and 54 (#9), Nov. 14, 1921
    - Resubdivision of Block 40 and Part of Block 42 (#10), Sept. 23, 1922
    - Lane and Subdivision of Lots 11, 12 and 13 Block 3 (#10), Feb. 27, 1923
    - Portion of Charlcote Place to be vacated (#11), Mar. 15, 1925
    - East Way Subdivision A-Resubdivision of part of Block 36 (#11), May 27, 1925
  - Homeland
    - Original Plat-Sheet #1, Jan. 1, 1925
    - Original Plat-Sheet #2, Jan. 1, 1925
    - Original Plat-Sheet #3, Jan. 1, 1925
    - Resubdivisons-pts. Blocks 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 31, 38 and 39 (#4), May 19, 1925
    - Resubdivisions-Blocks 2 and pts. 1, 3, 4, 5, 6 and 7 (#5), Apr. 26, 1926
    - Resubdivisions-pts. Blocks 29, 30, 37 and 41 (#6), May 25, 1926
    - Resubdivsions-Blocks 2A and pts. 22, 23, 24 and 25 (#7), Dec. 23, 1926
    - Sheet #4 of Homeland (West of Chas. St.) (#8), Feb. 8, 1927
    - Resubdivsion-Blocks 27 and pts. 8, 17, 18, 24, 32, 37, 40 and 41 (#9), June 22, 1927
    - Resubdivision-pts. Blocks 7, 8, 17, 27 and 29 (#10), Nov. 30, 1927
    - Resubdivision-pt. Block 25 (Paddington Court) (#11), Feb. 20, 1928
    - Resubdivision-pt. Block 37 (St. Dunstan's Court)(#5), July 26, 1928
    - Plat of-Blocks 46, 47, 48, 49 and Resubdivision pt. Blocks 42, 8, 9, 16, 17, 27 (#12), Dec. 28, 1928
    - Resubdivision-pt. Block 45 (#8), Feb. 25, 1929
    - Plat of-pt. Block 4 (alley closing W. of St. Albans Way)(#13), July 18, 1929
    - Resubdivsion-pt. Block 47 (#7), Apr. 23, 1930
    - Resubdivions-pt. Block 6 (Relocation of alley W. of St. Albans)(#14), Oct. 23, 1931
    - Plat of-pt. Block 4 (alley closing W. of St. Albans Way)(#2), Apr. 16, 1932
    - Block 50-Being a Resubdivions of pts. of Blocks 34 and 36 (#6), July 16, 1935
    - Plat of-Blocks 51, 52, 53, 54 and 55 (resubdivision of Blocks 33, 35 and pts. of Blocks 32 and 36)(#15), Jan. 27, 1937
    - Resubdivision-Pt. Block 34 (#14), Nov. 13, 1939
    - Resubdivision-Pt. Block 29 (#11), Aug. 23, 1928
    - Resubdivision-Pts. Blocks 48, 49 and 29 (#11), July 30, 1942